<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>public health | David Foxcroft PhD CPsychol</title>
    <link>/tags/public-health/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/public-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>public health</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© David Foxcroft 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 11:17:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>public health</title>
      <link>/tags/public-health/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>R stats</title>
      <link>/teaching/5-rstats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 11:17:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/teaching/5-rstats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a demand-led series of workshops run every year for PhD students, postgraduates and staff interested in getting to grips with R and RStudio for statistical analysis. Typical content includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installing R and RStudio and initial orientation&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting data in&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data wrangling, base and tidyverse approaches&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plotting data&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression in R&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculating sample size requirements&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayesian statistics in R (rstan)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence Based Prevention</title>
      <link>/teaching/4-ebp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 10:54:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/teaching/4-ebp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Non-communicable diseases such as cancer, heart disease, diabetes, chronic lung conditions, and mental illness pose a significant health and well-being burden for both the developed and the developing world. These diseases and conditions are often linked to behaviours, for example drinking, smoking, poor diet and exercise. Given this, policy makers and behavioural experts are increasingly interested in what sort of prevention approaches could be used to effectively reduce the burden of non-communicable diseases. In this module the aims are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To develop a critical understanding of psychological approaches to prevention.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide an objective analytical basis on which to build relevant prevention policies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To inform practitioners who have responsibility for prevention programming and delivery in local communities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To establish a basis for further research into prevention effectiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will appeal to those with intellectual and career development interests in behavioural health, mental health and wellbeing, public health preventive services, as well as the wider fields of public health, health policy, advocacy, social work, epidemiology, health and social care, teaching and community development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Research Methods - Systematic Reviews</title>
      <link>/teaching/3-sysreviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 10:46:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/teaching/3-sysreviews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a single MSc level half-module offered over one semester, introducing students to research methods that are used in public health in the context of systematic literature reviews. Topics covered include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asking the Right Question&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Primary Research Designs and Types of Bias (Experimental and Observational)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Systematic Reviews&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Literature Searching&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality Assesment, Risk of Bias and Data Extraction&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Synthesis (Meta-analysis, Narrative Synthesis, Realist Reviews)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health Equity assessment&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting systematic reviews&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
